No... A Prismer at the academy?
Wow!
Hey, Rani, that's a Prismer, right?
Yeah, it is...
It's moving! It's not like the one
we saw in Almen that was frozen!
When I was but an infant, I decided
that I'd one day defeat a Prismer on my own.
And now here it is, right before my eyes!
I'm so glad I was reborn to master the blade!
To be precise, it's not fully complete yet.
It's only a matter of time.
Oh, I just don't know!
Which should I fight?
Come on, Chris! What are you thinking?
We have to get back to
the academy, obviously!
Rani! B-But...
Get going.
This rat over here
was my prey from the start.
Hey, no fair, Ivel!
No stealing my opponents!
That thing will be annihilated
the moment it touches my shield!
Reborn
to Master the Blade
From Hero-King to Extraordinary Squire
Episode 12     Clash! Hero-King vs. King of Rainbows
This isn't good...
What's this thing?
Is this what they call a last boss?
Leone! Liselotte!
Get the people who fell
unconscious out of here!
Yes, ma'am!
Buy me a little time!
Yua, I'll put up a barrier.
Distract the Prismer.
I'm scared of the big guy, though...
I will not let you talk back right now!
Go do it!
O-Okay!
Nice work, girlie!
Hey, over here!
Good stuff.
Nice work, old man.
I'm actually still in my twenties...
The only thing to do with bad stuff
is get it over with as soon as you can.
Hai-yah!
Good! Nice punch!
Reminds me of Inglis!
No, I don't think it did anything.
Huh? Looks like you pierced
its skin, though.
No, I'm being sucked in. Suck-suck.
What? Seriously?
Yua!
I surrounded her with a barrier!
Okay, wait a second.
This'll hurt a little,
but I'll blow that whole area away!
ASAP, please.
Heat beam incoming! Run, everyone!
Brother!
Leon!
Are you okay?
I guess...
Bastard... That armor's
been my partner for years!
I'm kind of in trouble here...
Yua!
No...
She's still okay!
The barrier's working!
She hasn't been completely absorbed!
I'll find a way to dig her out!
Silva, how's Ripple looking?
She's not absorbing my power anymore.
This is likely the last magicite beast.
So we just have to survive this, then.
Won't Ripple be waking up soon?
If that happens, we can have her help...
No, I wouldn't count on that.
But why?
This is exactly what the
Hyral Menases are for!
She'll still be weak after what happened.
Don't make her exert herself.
That Prismer probably isn't complete.
Let's find another way!
Take everyone to a pocket space
where they'll be safe!
What will you do?
I'll figure things out.
If I go too, the barrier will disappear!
Go!
Brother...
Here I go!
You're responsible for
your own safety, okay?
Sure thing, "ma'am."
Here it comes!
I'll stop it!
Chris, we have to get back to the academy!
No, the others are there already.
They'll be fine.
It's important to believe in your comrades!
Good, the town's safe.
See?
I don't see!
You girls sure make a lot of noise.
Get back to your friends.
We don't have time to deal with you.
W-Wait! Please don't leave!
I still want to fight you...
Silence!
I'm not here for your entertainment,
nor am I your playmate.
We've achieved our goal
of killing the Highlander emissary
and taking his battleship.
That's enough for us. We're leaving.
It seems to be growing
more complete by the second.
You should hurry before it's too late.
Chris!
I'm disappointed.
I wanted to fight you more.
I'll pass.
You can have that as a gift from us. Go.
I'll see you again sometime.
I certainly hope not.
Ripple!
Guys, you're safe...
Not as much as you'd think.
The last magicite beast
summoned was a Prismer.
What? One of my comrades became a Prismer?
The principal said it wasn't
complete yet, but...
The principal and Leone's brother are
staying outside the pocket space to stop it.
Leon's here?
He came to help us.
Even those two aren't strong enough
to do this on their own!
Leone, can you cancel the pocket space?
Okay!
The school building...
Miliera! Leon! Are you okay?
Ripple! Good timing!
You awake now, Sleeping Beauty?
We're okay for now, barely, but help
would be more than appreciated!
Leave it to me.
I've caused problems for everyone...
so now I'll protect them in turn!
Because I'm a Hyral Menas!
Even if you were once my comrade...
No, because you were once my comrade...
I have to do this!
Wow.
She always did know how to move.
Ripple! Get out of here!
No!
Ripple!
No! It might hit Ripple!
Damn it!
What do we do, Miliera?
I don't know how long that barrier will last.
First, we need to get it out of the city
before the barrier breaks
and its beams can hit something!
Ripple!
I'm fine. Hyral Menases are tough.
If you want to get it out of the city,
I'll be the one to draw its attention.
You need to rest. I'll do that.
Please... I need to be the one to...
Ripple...
Please, become a weapon
and lend me your strength!
I can't do that!
I'm still in training, but I can do this!
Please!
Ever since you saved me when I was a child,
I've been training so that
I could fight with you some day!
I became strong, just like you told me to!
Silva...
I didn't think the little kid I saved
would become such a strong young man...
Time sure flies.
I've gotten older, too, haven't I?
You saved my life, and I want to repay you.
The Highlanders are
using you for their plots,
and forcing you to fight your comrades...
and I want to protect your heart!
Silva... But...
Ripple?
N-No! I wasn't trying to do it!
Stop it, Ripple! Don't turn into a weapon!
He's still too young!
N-No! I'm not the one who wants to do it...
His will is drawing me in!
Ripple...
Th-That's Ripple...
...in the form of a weapon.
I can feel it... Incredible power...
With this, I can defeat anything!
Even a Prismer!
Stop! Drop it!
Silva, calm down!
You can't let the power take control!
You're not ready to use that!
Ripple answered my request.
Get out of the way.
I said, put it down!
Don't get in my way!
Inglis?
Looks like I made it just in time!
How? In what possible way?
It looks more to me like you attacked one
of our allies before he could save the day!
Please don't break my barrier!
Here it comes! Miliera! Rebuild the barrier!
No! There's no time!
I'll take full responsibility!
Inglis?!
I guess I can't kick it as far as Ivel...
It didn't work! It's going to fire!
That's just what I was hoping it would do!
Come on, fire!
The beams are heading for the city...
This is bad!
The beams changed direction?
Wh-What's going on?
It's Inglis!
She's punching the beams!
All of you, disappear into the sky!
It's too fast to see...
In the fifteen years since I was reborn...
have I ever been this excited?
My partner's
a Prismer!
I couldn't be happier!
Chris is definitely trying to have fun.
Inglis! This isn't the time!
See that light?
Yua's been absorbed inside it!
Yua? Got it!
I'll focus my attacks around Yua
and dig her out!
L-Look! It's faster than when it fought me!
With a body that size...
I can't believe it!
I need to do more than
just dodge its attacks all day.
She blocked it?
It's not just fast! There's an incredible
weight behind each of its strikes!
Wonderful!
Uh, guys...
She's blocking the Prismer's punches
and kicks with her own...
Maybe she was really a Hyral Menas all along?
It looks like blocking is all
she can do, though...
There's no opening for me
to launch an attack of my own.
So...
Aether Pierce!
Aether Strike!
Inglis! The light of Yua's barrier
is growing weaker!
It's going to completely absorb her!
I have one thing that might do the trick.
I have to get close to try it...
but it's watching for that.
Chris!
Rani!
Leone! Liselotte!
We'll distract it!
That'll be your chance!
Here we go!
Aether Strike!
Even you can't dodge in mid-air!
That's what I've been waiting for!
It's working!
The rainbow-colored skin
is taking damage, too!
Go! Blow it away!
No!
Hang in there! Stand strong!
You can take this!
Chris!
Inglis!
Go!
Aether Breaker!
Is it over?
The Prismer... is defeated?
Wh-Where's Inglis?
She's fine!
I worked up a nice sweat today!
Hooray!
I'm so glad!
You did it, Inglis!
Nice work, Inglis!
You're the best!
I thought for a moment that when
it disappeared, it took Yua with it.
I'm amazed you were able to save her.
I pulled her out while I was
piercing through the Prismer.
That new technique is the
strongest you've ever used!
They're gonna let us eat free at the
cafeteria for even longer now, Chris!
Is that true, ma'am?
Y-Yes, of course it is!
I'm starving after all that fighting!
So let's go!
Huh?
Where's the cafeteria?
It got blown up.
You can eat your fill when it's rebuilt.
Several Days Later
Hey, you there.
Stop slacking, and work.
You didn't do anything
when the big guy showed up.
So you should do all the work here.
I would've beaten the Prismer
if I hadn't been interrupted!
You don't believe me, do you?
And what happened to the two girls who want
the cafeteria back more than anything?
They said they were going to the royal court.
The king summoned them himself!
Did you see what happened
when I turned into a weapon?
Yeah. That could've been a big problem.
So you knew what you were doing
when you stopped him.
If Silva had fired...
We would've paid a heavy price
for defeating the Prismer.
I don't know how I would've been able
to face everyone after that.
That's how the relationship between a holy
knight and a Hyral Menas works, right?
I finally understand why Eris got
so agitated when she met Rani.
Chris! I'm all ready!
Don't tell Rafinha that.
Of course.
Thank you both so much for your help.
You have my deepest gratitude.
Your words honor us, sire.
Especially you, Inglis.
You defeated the Highlander Arch Lord alone
and drove away the Bloodchain Brigade.
The judgment and decisiveness you showed
make you truly worthy
to lead my country's knights.
I'm honored... Huh?
Inglis Eucus, I hereby declare you
the new head of the Royal Guard.
You're making Chris the head
of the Royal Guard?
But...
Your power rivals that of a
Hyral Menas or holy knight.
None could be better suited for the job.
Congratulations, Lady Inglis!
Please become our leader!
Sure, Chris is strong, and decisive...
But... this means Chris won't
be with me anymore, right?
I should be happy she's getting
an offer like this, though!
I have to be happy for her...
But... But...
It's an honor, truly, but I must refuse.
Whaaa?
Wh-What?
You're sure about this, Chris?
I already decided to always be by your side.
So it doesn't bother me at all.
You're saying that, but the real
reason is that the commander
doesn't get a lot of chances to
fight on the front lines, right?
You could tell, huh?
Chris, let's be friends forever, okay?
Yeah, let's do our best together, Rani!
Now, let's go home.
Yeah.
Wait, you two.
We're not done talking yet.
I wanted to bring you here
to thank you for your efforts yesterday.
This feast was actually intended to celebrate
Inglis's appointment as commander, but yeah.
You're not going to turn
this down too, are you?
Not at all, Your Majesty!
We accept with pleasure!
Now, let's both say it together...
Meat!
Comic by Kuromura Moto